In the last video we learned some basics about how the heap works and now we want to apply
在上一个视频中，我们学习了堆如何工作的一些基本知识，现在我们要应用
this to heap level 1 from exploit-exercsies protostar to solve it.
这是为了将1级从剥削堆到原始星来解决它。
Actually I want try something.
实际上我想试试。
We do some roleplaying.
我们做一些角色扮演。
Let’s first be the security researcher who want’s to find a bug to exploit in this
让我们先做一个安全研究员，他想找到一个可以利用的漏洞
binary.
二元的。
Afterwards we play developer trying to understand the exploit to fix the issue.
之后，我们扮演开发人员的角色，试图理解解决问题的漏洞。
So we put on our black hoodie and get started… first we open the binary heap1 in gdb and
所以我们穿上黑色的连帽衫开始…首先我们在gdb中打开二进制堆1
execute it.
执行它。
We get a segfault.
我们得到一个SegFault。
And it also shows us that the segfault was caused by strcpy, because it tried to copy
同时也说明SEGCFAULT是由strcpy引起的，因为它试图复制
a string from the address 0, to this other address here, and 0 is obviously not valid
从地址0到这里的另一个地址0的字符串显然无效
memory - so it crashes.
内存-所以它崩溃了。
We know how linux binaries work, so we make an educated guess that this application might
我们知道Linux二进制文件是如何工作的，所以我们有根据地猜测这个应用程序可能
require some input and we try the arguments.
需要一些输入，我们尝试参数。
Run with aaaa.
和AAAA一起跑步。
Again another segfault, but the attentive viewer will notice that the address is now
又是另一个segfault，但是细心的观察者会注意到地址现在是
different, so this is a different strcpy, which again can’t copy from address 0, so
不同，所以这是一个不同的strcpy，它同样不能从地址0复制，所以
we guess that it requires another argument.
我们认为这需要另一个论点。
And this time the program runs through without errors.
这一次程序运行无误。
Now we try to find a bug, so the simplest thing to do is, we just throw some long inputs
现在我们试图找到一个bug，所以最简单的事情就是，我们只需要抛出一些长的输入
at the program and see if something happens.
在程序中查看是否发生了什么。
So for the first argument I choose to do a pattern with letters and for the second argument
所以对于第一个参数，我选择用字母做一个模式，对于第二个参数
I do numbers, just so I could idnetify them if something would occur.
我做数字，只是为了在有事情发生的时候能识别它们。
We run that, and we got a different segfault.
我们运行它，得到一个不同的segfault。
Again because of strcpy, but this time the destination address looks invalid.
同样是因为strcpy，但这次目标地址看起来无效。
It tried to copy the string with the numbers, which we know is the second argument, to the
它试图将带有数字的字符串（我们知道这是第二个参数）复制到
address 46,46,46,46 which is the hexcode for FFFF.
地址46,46,46,46，它是ffff的十六进制代码。
So whatever happened, we somehow overwrote an address, that is used as the destination
所以不管发生什么，我们以某种方式重写了一个用作目的地的地址
of the strcpy.
对的。
And this means we can now use the first argument to fully control where we want to write.
这意味着我们现在可以使用第一个参数来完全控制我们想写的地方。
And we can fully choose what to write, with the second argument.
通过第二个论点，我们可以完全选择要写什么。
Now we have a lot of freedom what we want to overwrite.
现在我们有了很多自由，我们想要覆盖的东西。
For example we can overwrite the return pointer on the stack to redirect code execution, or
例如，我们可以覆盖堆栈上的返回指针来重定向代码执行，或者
we can overwrite an entry of the global offset table, which I explained in a previous video,
我们可以覆盖全局偏移表的一个条目，我在前面的视频中解释过，
to achieve the same.
达到同样的效果。
Let’s do the latter one, it’s usually more reliable than the stack - which likes
让我们来做后一个，它通常比堆栈更可靠，后者喜欢
to move around.
四处走动
So let’s check what kind of function is called after the evil strcpy.
那么让我们检查一下在邪恶的strcpy之后调用了什么类型的函数。
We can peak into the source code and see that there is a printf, and we could assume that
我们可以到达源代码的峰值，看到有一个printf，我们可以假设
we want to overwrite printf on the global offset table, but that is deceiving.
我们想覆盖全局偏移表上的printf，但这是欺骗。
That’s not the case.
事实并非如此。
So let’s better stick to the assembly.
所以我们最好还是坚持到大会上吧。
First of all we have to find the location from were we were calling the strcpy.
首先，我们要找到的位置是我们打电话给strcpy。
We can use backtrace for that, which will look at the stack and the stored return pointers
我们可以使用backtrace，它将查看堆栈和存储的返回指针
to figure out where we are - as a sidenote, if you found a bug that smashes the stack,
为了弄清楚我们在哪里——作为旁注，如果你发现了一个破坏堆栈的错误，
then backtrace can not make much sense of it anymore.
那么回溯就不再有什么意义了。
So it doesn’t always work.
所以它并不总是有效的。
And here we can see that currently we are in strcpy, but we were coming from this address.
在这里我们可以看到我们现在在Strcpy，但我们来自这个地址。
So let’s set the disassemblu flavor to sane intel syntax and disasemble the address.
因此，让我们设置disassemblu风格，使英特尔语法正常，并分解地址。
This will now disassemble the whole function this address belongs to.
这将分解这个地址所属的整个函数。
Our address ended in 5a, so we are here after the strcpy.
我们的地址以5a结尾，所以我们在strcpy后面。
And as you can see there is a call to puts next.
正如你所看到的，接下来有一个电话要拨。
Which btw is not printf like in the source code.
在源代码中，btw与printf不同。
That’s because the compiler replaced the printf with puts for optimization reasons.
这是因为编译器出于优化的原因用puts替换了printf。
Ok, so let’s overwrite the global offset table entry for puts.
好的，那么让我们覆盖Puts的全局偏移表条目。
As shown in the got video we can figure out the address of puts by first disassembling
如got视频所示，我们可以通过首先分解找出放置的地址。
the function trapoline in the procedure linkage table, which would now jump to an address
过程链接表中的函数trapoline，现在将跳转到一个地址
stored at this address.
存储在这个地址。
So this means this is the address of the puts global offset table entry.
这意味着这是Puts全局偏移表条目的地址。
So this is the target we want to write to, thus we place it in the first argument.
所以这是我们要写的目标，所以我们把它放在第一个论点中。
gdb run, but we use backticks in the first argument to execute /bin/echo.
gdb运行，但我们在第一个参数中使用backticks来执行/bin/echo。
As you know echo simply outputs whatever you pass to it as arguments, and we can use that
正如您所知，echo只输出您作为参数传递给它的任何内容，我们可以使用它
to get characters with hexvalues we can’t type.
要获取十六进制值的字符，我们不能键入。
For example the hex value 8.
例如十六进制值8。
So echo -ne, -n because we don’t want that echo places a newline at the end of the output.,
所以echo-ne，-n是因为我们不希望echo在输出的末尾放置新行。
and -e because we want echo to convert hex escaped numbers into the raw characters.
和-e，因为我们希望echo将十六进制转义数转换为原始字符。
Just to make sure everything works we echo the whole test string up to the Fs again.
为了确保一切正常，我们再次将整个测试字符串回送到fs。
Now echo inside of the backticks will be executed and the output of that will be placed inside
现在将执行backticks中的echo，并将其输出放入
of the quotes as the first argument.
作为第一个参数。
And when we run this we get the same segfault as before, so all is fine.
当我们运行这个程序时，会得到和以前一样的segfault，所以一切都很好。
Next step is obviously to replace the Fs with the address of the puts global offset table
下一步显然是用puts全局偏移表的地址替换fs。
entry.
条目。
And when we now run it we get a segfault somehwere else, this time because of 30303030, which
当我们现在运行它的时候，我们在其他地方得到一个SegFault，这次是因为30303030，它
is ascii for 0000.
是ASCII表示0000。
And when we look at the registers with info registers we can see that we sucessfully got
当我们用信息寄存器查看寄存器时，我们可以看到我们成功地得到了
control of EIP, which means we can now redirect code anywhere we want.
控制EIP，这意味着我们现在可以将代码重定向到我们想要的任何地方。
In this case we want to call winner, winner has this address here.
在这种情况下，我们要打电话给Winner，Winner在这里有这个地址。
So we place that into the second argument instead of argv2 by using echo in backticks.
所以我们把它放在第二个参数中，而不是argv2中，在backticks中使用echo。
We execute it and we get winner.
我们执行它，我们就获得了胜利。
Which also works great outside of gdb.
它在gdb之外也很有效。
In summary we can say this: we identified a bug by guessing and playing
总之，我们可以这样说：我们通过猜测和玩来识别一个bug
around with it.
围绕着它。
Through gdb we learned that somehow we can control the destination of a strcpy, and we
通过gdb，我们了解到我们可以通过某种方式控制strcpy的目的地，并且我们
learned we even control what we want to copy.
学会了我们甚至控制我们想要复制的东西。
And we abused that to overwrite the function address of puts to redirect code execution
我们滥用它来覆盖puts的函数地址来重定向代码执行。
to the winner function.
到Winner函数。
All without knowing why this even happened and not even knowing that the heap was involved
都不知道为什么会发生这种情况，甚至不知道涉及堆
at all.
完全。
Being a good security researcher we create a writeup, an advisory for this.
作为一名优秀的安全研究员，我们为此撰写了一份报告和建议。
Providing our proof of concept exploit as well as some additional information that might
提供概念验证利用以及一些可能
help the developer.
帮助开发者。
Now let’s change sides and become the developer.
现在让我们改变立场，成为开发者。
We take off our black hoodie, and put on our grey hoodie.
我们脱下黑色的连帽衫，穿上灰色的连帽衫。
Because that's what developers wear.
因为开发人员就是这么穿的。
So we just got this email from this dude who found a bug in our program.
所以我们刚收到这个家伙发来的邮件，他在我们的程序中发现了一个错误。
He even provided a Proof of Concept exploit with it.
他甚至用它提供了概念利用的证据。
Now we want to figure out why and how this happened, so we can fix it.
现在我们想知道为什么会发生这种情况，以及如何发生，这样我们就可以解决它了。
In the advisory it says that it has to do something with strcpy.
在公告中，它说它与strcpy有关。
So we read the manual about strcpy.
所以我们读了关于strcpy的手册。
And have this “oh shit” moment when we realized we didn’t even read the documentation
当我们意识到我们甚至没有阅读文档时，就有了这个“噢，该死的”时刻。
that would have told us what a bad idea that was.
那会告诉我们这是个多么糟糕的主意。
So now we could fix that.
现在我们可以解决这个问题了。
For example using strncpy or use strlen to check the length before we copy it and then
例如，在复制之前使用strncpy或使用strlen检查长度，然后
exit.
出口。
But because we are a good developer we try to learn from this advisory and try to understand
但是因为我们是一个优秀的开发人员，所以我们试图从这个建议中学习并理解
how the exploit exactly works.
该漏洞是如何工作的。
In the last video, the heap malloc introduction video, we already thought about how the heap
在上一个视频，堆malloc介绍视频中，我们已经考虑了堆
should look like from this program.
从这个程序中应该是这样的。
So let’s see how it looks in reality.
让我们看看它在现实中的样子。
To do this let’s set a breakpoint after each malloc and strcpy.
为此，我们在每个malloc和strcpy之后设置一个断点。
We dissasemble main and look for all those calls and set breakpoints afterwards.
我们分解main并查找所有这些调用，然后设置断点。
Then we run it with the proof of concept exploit arguments.
然后我们用概念证明来运行它，利用论点。
And we hit the first breakpoint.
我们到达了第一个断点。
So now the first malloc happened.
所以现在第一个malloc发生了。
So we are currently here in the assembler code and the result of malloc is in eax.
所以我们现在在汇编代码中，malloc的结果在eax中。
So eax contains the address on the heap where we have enough space for the internet struct
所以eax包含堆上的地址，在那里我们有足够的空间用于Internet结构
i1.
I1.
And we can look at this address and we can see it’s simply 0.
我们可以看到这个地址，它只是0。
With info proc mappings we can see the memory segments, and there is also the heap and we
使用info-proc映射，我们可以看到内存段，还有堆和
can have a look at that.
可以看看那个。
Oh, maybe it’s a good idea to add this heap output as a gdb hook as well.
哦，也许把这个堆输出添加为gdb挂钩也是个好主意。
So we see it automatically at each breakpoint.
所以我们会在每个断点自动看到它。
define hook-stop x/64wx 0x
定义挂钩停止X/64WX 0x
end
结束
So if we now continue we should set the priority of i1 to 1, and then malloc for the name.
因此，如果我们现在继续，我们应该将I1的优先级设置为1，然后将malloc设置为名称。
Let’s have a closer look at the heap.
让我们仔细看看这个堆。
So as we learned the i1 variable points here.
所以我们在这里学习了I1变量点。
So this is where the struct starts and you can se that the first attribute, which is
所以这就是结构开始的地方，您可以将第一个属性
the priority is set to 1.
优先级设置为1。
And before that we have the heap metadata, the chunk header, which contains the lnegth
在此之前，我们有堆元数据，即块头，其中包含
of this chunk, including the last bit set to 1 which means that the previous block is
包括最后一位设置为1，这意味着前一个块
not free.
不是免费的。
It’s in use.
它正在使用中。
And what we see is what we expected, we see here two chunks of 8 bytes, including the
我们看到的是我们所期望的，我们在这里看到两个8字节的块，包括
headers it’s obviously 16 bytes.
头，显然是16字节。
Another cool thing we can do is to define a variable i1 in gdb and set it to the address
我们可以做的另一件很酷的事情是在gdb中定义一个变量i1并将其设置为地址
of this object.
这个物体的
Aaand we can even add the type of this variable which is “struct internet”.
aa我们甚至可以添加这个变量的类型“struct internet”。
Now we can print this variable i1 and gdb can display us the attributes priority and
现在我们可以打印这个变量i1，gdb可以显示属性priority和
name.
姓名。
And we can see that priority is 1, and name is still zero, because we have allocated memory
我们可以看到优先级是1，名称仍然是零，因为我们已经分配了内存
for the name but not yet assigned it to the i1 attribute name.
但尚未将其分配给i1属性名。
If we continue to the next breakpoint the address of the name got assigned and the i2
如果我们继续到下一个断点，将分配名称的地址和I2
object got allocated.
对象已分配。
And the result of malloc is again in eax, that’s the address of the i2 object.
malloc的结果再次出现在eax中，这就是i2对象的地址。
So we can also define the variable i2 in gdb.
所以我们也可以在gdb中定义变量i2。
And when we print that we can see that it’s still empty.
当我们打印的时候，我们可以看到它仍然是空的。
Now if we continue the priority of i2 should be set to two, which we can verify by looking
现在，如果我们继续，I2的优先级应该设置为2，我们可以通过查看来验证
at the heap memory as well when we print the i2 object.
当我们打印I2对象的时候，也在堆内存中。
Also all of our 4 mallocs are done now.
我们的4个malloc现在都完成了。
And if we compare that to what we expected in the earlier video, we can see that it fits
如果我们将其与之前视频中的预期进行比较，我们会发现它符合
perfectly.
完美。
There is only one thing that we didn’t talk about yet, and that’s this big value after
只有一件事我们还没有讨论过，那就是在
all chunks at the end.
最后的所有块。
Well this area down here is all free memory and in exploitation terms this is often referred
好吧，下面这个区域是所有的空闲内存，用剥削的术语来说，这经常被提到
to as the wilderness.
像荒野一样。
This is number is the remaining size of the heap.
这是数字，是堆的剩余大小。
This whole thing is basically a huge heap chunk, and that number is its length.
这整个东西基本上是一个巨大的堆块，这个数字就是它的长度。
I made a three part video about the cookbook challenge from a ctf, and that exploit abuses
我制作了一个由三部分组成的关于CTF挑战食谱的视频，其中利用了滥用
this number to redirect code execution.
此数字用于重定向代码执行。
It’s super awesome.
太棒了。
You should watch it.
你应该看看。
Anyway.
不管怎样。
Right now the name of i1 is still an empty string.
现在，i1的名称仍然是一个空字符串。
But this is about to change with the next breakpoint.
但这将随着下一个断点而改变。
Because we are about to execute the first strcpy, which copies this super long first
因为我们要执行第一个strcpy，它首先复制这个超长的
argument.
争论。
Continue.
继续。
Now first thing we notice is here in the heap memory.
现在我们注意到的第一件事是堆内存中。
Those ascii characters appear and it looks like they have overwritten a lot of stuf on
这些ASCII字符出现了，看起来它们覆盖了很多stuf
the heap.
堆。
What earlier was supposed to be chunk header metadata, like the size is now 44444444.
之前应该是块头元数据，比如现在的大小是444444。
Let’s have a look at the objects i1 and i2.
让我们看看对象I1和I2。
So i1 looks fine, i1 has still priority 1 and name with the string that we passed to
所以i1看起来很好，i1仍然具有优先级1和名称以及我们传递给的字符串
it.
它。
How about i2?
I2怎么样？
Uh… that looks fucked.
呃……看起来他妈的。
Priority is now a super huge number.
优先权现在是一个巨大的数字。
In fact that’s just 45454545 in decimal, and that’s the Es.
事实上，小数点后只有454545，这就是es。
And the name is 46464646, which we know are Fs.
它的名字是46464646，我们知道它是fs。
And yeah, we seem to have overwritten a lot of stuff on the heap.
是的，我们似乎覆盖了堆中的很多东西。
Infact we have overwritten the next chunk on the heap after the i1 name.
实际上，我们已经覆盖了堆中I1名称后面的下一个块。
And now the next strcpy will take i2-&gt;name, which is pointing to some bad memory and try
现在下一个strcpy将采用i2-&gt；名称，它指向一些坏内存并尝试
to copy there the 2nd argument.
复制第二个参数。
Really frckn awesome.
真是太棒了。
So this challenge showed one aspect of heap exploits.
所以这个挑战展示了堆利用的一个方面。
It doesn’t attack the heap algorithm itself, it attacks the application, which uses objects
它不攻击堆算法本身，而是攻击使用对象的应用程序
on the heap that we can modify by overwriting stuff.
在堆上，我们可以通过重写东西来修改。
And those modified objects then bend the execution flow.
然后这些修改过的对象会弯曲执行流。
Cool, huh?
很酷，是吧？